Sci-fi movies tend to capture children's imaginations and have long been part of students' excited chats in the schoolyard.
科幻电影往往能吸引孩子们的想象力，并长期以来成为学生们在校园里兴奋讨论的话题。
But now a scientific journal has urged at least one sci-fi movie to be shown in class by science teachers.
但现在，一份科学期刊呼吁科学教师至少在课堂上放映一部科幻电影。
Scientific papers published in the American Journal of Physics (AJP) and in Classical and Quantum Gravity have seen merit in the way the movie Interstellar portrays wormholes.
发表在《美国物理学杂志》（AJP）和《经典与量子引力》上的科学论文认为，电影《星际穿越》对虫洞描绘的方式很有价值。
Dr David Jackson from AJP said publishing this paper "was a no-brainer".
AJP的大卫·杰克逊博士表示，发表这篇论文“是理所当然的”。
He added: "The physics has been very carefully reviewed by experts and found to be accurate.
他补充说：“电影中的物理内容已经经过专家的仔细审查，并被发现是准确的。
The publication will encourage physics teachers to show the film in their classes to get across ideas about general relativity".
这篇论文将鼓励物理教师在课堂上放映这部电影，以传达广义相对论的概念。”
In fact, one of the executive producers of Interstellar was Kip Thorne, a professor of theoretical physics at the California Institute of Technology (Caltech).
事实上，《星际穿越》的执行制片人之一是加州理工学院（Caltech）的理论物理学教授基普·索恩（Kip Thorne）。
For him, films such as Interstellar, Contact and 2001: A Space Odyssey can inspire young people.
对他来说，像《星际穿越》、《接触》和《2001太空漫游》这样的电影可以激励年轻人。
Blockbusters are improving when it comes to portraying scientific theories.
在描绘科学理论方面，大片正在不断进步。
An initiative by the US National Academy of Sciences has been putting proper scientists in touch with movie people to achieve a better result – which is vital in the internet age.
美国国家科学院的一项倡议一直以来让真正的科学家与电影人接触，以取得更好的效果——这在互联网时代至关重要。
Interstellar's director Christopher Nolan says: "Consumers have a lot more immediate access to information.
《星际穿越》的导演克里斯托弗·诺兰说：“消费者可以更直接地获取信息。
If you go and see a film about a particular subject, particularly a true life story, you can go home and look it up on Wikipedia and see if the basic things portrayed in the film are true or not.
如果你去看一部关于特定主题的电影，尤其是一个真实的故事，你可以回家后在维基百科上查找，看看电影中描绘的基本内容是否真实。
The same is true of science in the films".
电影中的科学也是如此。”
Professional scientists may no longer cringe in their seats when they watch sci-fi movies.
专业科学家在观看科幻电影时可能不再会在座位上感到尴尬。
Today, getting the science wrong is no longer an option.
如今，已经不再允许科学内容继续出错。